Preliminary Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office Records, 1947-1999 and undated RL.00682
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office records
1947-1999 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office
RL.00682
50 Linear Feet
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Co. Archives: Detroit Office Records was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1989-2002.
Historical Note
The J. Walter Thompson Company was founded in New York, N.Y., in 1864, and is one of the world's largest advertising agencies.
Collection Overview
Collection contains miscellaneous files from the Detroit office; tearsheets, client and competitive advertising. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising and Marketing History.
Slides (photographs); Motion pictures (visual works); Automobiles -- United States; Automobiles -- Marketing; Photographs; Ford automobile -- Marketing -- History; Ford automobile -- Marketing; Advertising -- Automobiles -- United States; Advertising agencies -- History; Color transparencies; Advertising -- History; United States. Environmental Protection Agency; Ford Motor Company; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office
- Accession 93-015
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Unpublished materials less than 15 years old are closed to non-JWT researchers.
  - Historical Files. Ford truck components 1960s (Box 5)
    Scope and Contents note
    Engineering and standards information for axles, engines, misc. other components, and Recreational Vehicles.
  - Competitive Advertisements, Trucks, 1970s-1980s (Box 11)
    - Mack (Box 11)
    - Mazda (Box 11)
    - Peterbuilt (Box 11)
    - Plymouth (Box 11)
    - Toyota (Box 11)
    - Dodge (Box 11)
    - GMC (Box 11)
    - Datsun (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
    - Recreational Vehicles, Older Trucks (Box 11)
    - Brockway (Box 11)
    - Chevrolet (Box 11)
    - Freight Linear (Box 11)
    - Jeep (Box 11)
    - Kenworth (Box 11)
  - Competitive Advertisements, Trucks, 1970s-1980s (cont.) (Box 12)
    - White (Box 12)
  - Canadian Advertisements, Ford trucks
    - Fleet (Box 12)
    - Leasing (Box 12)
    - Motor-Homes (Box 12)
    - Rent-a-Car (Box 12)
    - Campers (Box 12)
    - Maximum Duty Trucks (Box 12)
    - Heavy Duty Trucks (Box 12)
  - Ford historical ads (Box 74)
  - Misc. slides and photographs, 1970s-1980s (Box 74)
- Accession 2002-0202
  - Contents of Box 5 (Box 5)